Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
Today is another day that the Lord has made.
And we want to do a little bit of good, to change the bad that we see.
Remember, love never gets tired of doing good because that love is the strength of God.
Like the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua says, Love always looks around.
Love always searches to see who is in need.
That is what we're doing today, here in the United States of America; in the state of Ohio.
We have got a special event tonight whereby we will be going into the low income neighbourhoods
meeting some of the disabled and elderly and we will be providing them with some goods.
Emmanuel TV Team sets up for the Charity Event.
As you can see right here, we've got some live produce; we have baskets of groceries.
The reason why we have baskets of groceries is because a lot of the elderly have expressed this to us,
that they really need some baskets for laundry as well.
So we were able to accomplish two things at once.
I am going to show you some of the things that we have here.
We have macaroni and cheese, chips, bread, eight pound bags of potatoes, bananas and water.
If you look over here, we have a Backpack Program for the youth.
We have the Emmanuel TV backpacks.
The Backpack Program has Emmanuel TV backpacks that have the words 'Keep watching Emmanuel TV" -
"Changing lives. Changing nations. Changing the world" - printed on them.
The bag also has all of the Emmanuel TV social media contacts on it - Facebook, Twitter, YouTube.
It has the main website as well, Instagram and the Emmanuel TV email address on it.
We did this so that people could stay connected. This Backpack Program is for the students.
It is for Elementary, Middle School and High School students.
We got this Backpack Program for them because many of them are only able to eat at school during lunch.
Some of them can get breakfast but most of them don't. They are able to eat their lunch.
But many of them when they are coming back home are coming into an environment where there is no food.
Especially on the weekend. Therefore the man of God has made it possible,
and provided the resources. So that we can help the youth to stay healthy and not have to worry about food.
They can go ahead to school and get an education.
So we want to show you some of the goods that we have for the Backpack Program.
We make sure that they have water, healthy drinks, packs of oatmeal for a good breakfast.
We also provide cheese crackers; making sure that they have granola bars.
Over here we have some noodles, these are basically meals that they can quickly make for themselves.
We ensure they have boxes of cereal. To ensure they stay as healthy as possible, we have real cheese sticks.
We've provided yogurt packs. For meat, we've provided tuna cans and canned sausage.
One of the other things that the parents can help with is this vegetable barley soup.
That's already been put together. To prepare, the parents can just pour it all in.
This soup is enough to serve ten full meals.
It is very good. We have tried it ourselves and it is very delicious. It is a vegetable barley soup.
They are getting this kind of meal as well.
They will be getting pudding and other healthy little items.
Apple sauce and some snacks like graham crackers and fruit snacks as well.
They have more snacks like chips and so forth.
And that is what happens with the Backpack Program.
They will be able to take this back pack and be able to come every time they need food.
They will be able to come back with the backpack and we will be able to continue to fill it.
So that's what the Backpack Program is about. The Emmanuel TV Backpack.
Now I also want to show you what we will be having in the baskets as well. So come this way.
At the food pantry located inside the Emmanuel TV USA office,
the Emmanuel TV team removes frozen packs of meat from the deep freezer,
wearing protective masks and gloves.
Through the assistance of Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV Partners,
the pantry is always fully stocked with various food items,
in preparation to carry out Christ's mission to feed the needy.
Emmanuel TV Team Prepares Packs Of Frozen Meat For Charity Event.
After being removed from the freezer, they tear open the larger packs of frozen meat.
One by one the frozen hamburger patties, chicken fingers, tenders and other meat,
are carefully placed into individual bags for each person who will receive them.
The Emmanuel TV Team give their quality time, quality love and quality care,
knowing that when you give love in truth, you are planting seeds that will be multiplied back to you.
Emmanuel TV Team Prepares Packs Of Frozen Meat For Charity Event.
As Christians, we should spend more on others and less on ourselves.
That is the only way that we can commit more faith and love in the society of which we are a part.
Love looks around to see those who are in need. These packs of frozen meat are just one of the many items,
that the Emmanuel TV Team is planning to distribute to those in need.
Emmanuel TV Team Prepares Packs Of Frozen Meat For Charity Event.
The book of James says that we must back up our faith with good deeds
for faith without good deeds is dead.
And our faith works by love. Therefore, we should love for God's sake and be loved.
Help for God's sake and be helped. Be kind for God's sake and receive kindness.
All this meat is going to be given away. This meat has hamburger patties, chicken fingers and tenders as well.
We have chicken patties also. We just have a whole lot of meat here.
That will do good for them as well.
You can see we have a whole bag full of meat. That's what we will be doing today.
We will be carrying you along and make sure you're able to see everything that is going on.
Emmanuel! (Matthew 1:23 - God is with us). Stay in faith.
Emmanuel TV Team Lays Out Backpacks For Filling And Distribution.
The team effort continues inside the Emmanuel TV USA Office facilities.
As the Emmanuel TV Team lays out backpacks and baskets for the Emmanuel TV Backpack Program,
the blue Emmanuel TV backpacks are neatly arranged in an orderly manner on the floor.
Next up, it's time to fill the baskets with the food stuffs provided by Prophet T.B. Joshua,
and the Emmanuel TV Partners.
Bags of potatoes are the first items to be loaded into the baskets. Each basket gets its own bag.
These baskets are a two-fold blessing.
They're not only for carrying food items but can be reused for laundry purposes.
Here come some more food items. Ripe bananas - a good source of fibre and energy for the grateful receivers.
Loaves of bread are the next food item, followed by tortilla chips.
A variety of chips are available.
Emmanuel TV Team Sharing Out Groceries Into Laundry Baskets For Charity Event.
The next task at hand involves loading the grocery baskets into the vehicles
in preparation for the charity event.
Emmanuel TV Team Loading Grocery Baskets Into Vehicles Ready For Transportation To Charity Event.
Once all the items have been loaded, the Emmanuel TV Team are set and make their journey to the charity event.
Emmanuel TV Team En Route to Charity Event Location.
Emmanuel TV Team Sets Up At Charity Event.
And finally, they arrive at the venue for the event - the Middle Town Public Housing Complex.
The Emmanuel TV Team begins to offload the baskets of food items from the vehicles.
Emmanuel TV Team Sets Up At Charity Event.
The needy residents of the housing complex come out to attend the charity event,
and line up eagerly, waiting to receive the goods from the Emmanuel TV Team.
Residents Of The Apartment Block Attend The Charity Event
I have a child in my apartment.
Just one?
Yes.
Ok, here you go.
Thank you, Sir.
You're Welcome
And here's a small gift.
Emmanuel TV Team Gives Out Grocery Baskets And Cash Gifts.
Love has a language that transcends all languages, cultures, barriers and distance.
Love is the greatest Christian virtue.
Emmanuel TV Team Gives Out Grocery Baskets And Cash Gifts.
Thank you, God Bless you!
God bless you too.
Do you need help in taking the groceries up?
Oh no, I'll be fine. Thank you!
Emmanuel TV Team Gives Out Grocery Baskets And Cash Gifts.
Do you need help in taking the groceries up?
Yes.
Ok, no problem.
Here's a cash gift.
Emmanuel TV Team Gives Out Grocery Baskets And Cash Gifts.
Do you need help in taking the groceries up?
Yes.
Ok, what room number are you in?
Room 608
608, you said?
Yes.
Emmanuel TV Team Gives Out Grocery Baskets And Cash Gifts.
Alright, we'll bring it right up to you. Ok.
Ok, thank you.
Emmanuel TV Team Gives Out Grocery Baskets And Cash Gifts.
Emmanuel, (God with us - Matthew 1:23) viewers! Indeed, God is with us.
And of course we're reporting live, all the way from the USA.
We're here in Ohio in the city of Middletown. I've got some very special guests with us right now.
I'm going to start by first asking his name. Brother, can you please tell me your name?
Jeff.
Ok Jeff, tell me where you're from?
I'm from Hamilton, Ohio.
I would like to ask you what you think about today.
You saw people coming to get some groceries and cash gifts.
There are about 80 apartments in this building and people came out by the masses and partook.
Tell me - how do you feel about that?
Well, I think it was a Godsent thing. And it was a blessing.
Some of us are struggling, not as fortunate as others. What you guys do is beautiful.
Thank you
Tell me the different people that we have here. We've got the disabled, and what other conditions are there?
We have the elderly, disabled, people that are unemployed, homeless
and people who are just struggling - scraping finger to toe - trying to make it everyday in life.
Just doing what we can to survive.
I noticed that some of the people that came and partook of the groceries and cash gifts are people that
came and helped other people as well. As far as staying with them.
There are one or two bedrooms, not mansions but many of you are taking in other people to stay with you, right?
Yes, this building is like an 84 or 86 apartment building.
Black, white, all different races - it doesn't matter - red, blue, green and yellow. We all stick together.
and whatever it takes, if I'm eating, you can eat and if I have a shirt, you don't have one,
you can get one and vice versa. We just look out for each other.
Great, that is what we saw. We saw everybody come and partake.
That goes without words.
I could never thank you enough, but T.B. Joshua, you are a blessing to us and many others.
God bless you for everything that you did.
Alright. You heard it from our brother and I want you to know that relationship is supposed to be for a lifetime.
I am hoping that this one will be.
So we will continue.
I would love that.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Emmanuel, (God with us - Matthew 1:23) viewers! Here we are once again and I have got a very special guest.
Of course today, we just had the event of being able to feed this housing development.
There are about 86 apartments in this building and a very special sister came aboard and began to help us.
She put her hands in and began to tote bags to different apartments of the ones that could not come down.
She took up the groceries and has done a great job. I will start by asking her name. Sister, what is your name?
My name is Eunice Thomas.
Tell me where are you from?
I'm from Cincinnati, Ohio.
Wow, Cincinnati, of course, is about 35 - 40 minutes from here.
Tell us about your experience today. What did you see?
People needed you.
It was a blessing that you guys came.
There are a lot of people struggling, like myself.
Some people have no income, some people are disabled, trying to get disability support, I'm a widow.
There are a lot of elderly people also and people with kids.
There are a lot of people that work but still can't make ends meet.
A lot of people team up in one household to try and make ends meet.
So anything that they can be helped with, they would be grateful.
Wow, you said a mouthful there. You said that you are a widow and are waiting for assistance to be helped.
So when you see charity organisations like this, it's a big help, right?
I appreciate it.
Before you came, I was really depressed and didn't know what today or tomorrow would bring.
When you came, it brightened me up. Thank you.
We thank you so much. The support comes all the way from Nigeria. From the man of God T.B. Joshua.
T.B. Joshua, thank you very much.
If there is anything I can do beyond this, don`t hesitate to contact me; I`m available.
My sister, we thank you so very much for putting your hands to the plow helping us in feeding everyone today.
Once again - Emmanuel (God With Us - Matthew 1:23), viewers!
We are right here in Middletown Ohio, doing a little bit of good to change the bad we see.
Emmanuel!
Emmanuel TV Team Taking Gifts To Those Unable To Attend The Event.
( knocking )
Hello!
How are you?
I'm good. Thank you very much!
You're welcome!
Here's a cash gift for you ma'am.
Thank you, have a blessed day.
You too.
Emmanuel TV Team Taking Gifts To Those Unable To Attend The Event.
Going down?
No. Going right here.
(laughing)
Emmanuel TV Team Taking Gifts To Those Unable To Attend The Event.
(Knocking)
Did you get yours already?
Yes I did.
Ok, we're just making sure, ok?
Ok, thank you!
Ok ma'am, we didn't want to forget anybody.
Ok, you have a good evening.
You too!
God bless you!
Emmanuel TV Team Taking Gifts To Those Unable To Attend The Event.
(knocking)
Hey, we have your bag for you.
Emmanuel TV Team Taking Gifts To Those Unable To Attend The Event.
There was a gemtleman who asked if we could bring him some groceries.
And we have a cash gift too.
Oh wow!
How are you doing , sir?
Good. I really appreciate it. Thank you.
God bless you!
God bless you, brother!
Here's a cash gift for you.
Wow, thank you so much!
Thank you!
You take care!
Thank you, you too!
The Emmanuel TV Team commences the Emmanuel TV Backpack Program,
delivering the Emmanuel TV Backpacks to students at the Lakota Pointe Government Housing Estate, Ohio, USA.
Emmanuel, viewers! Here we are in the West Chester area of Ohio, a subdivision of the Cincinnati area.
This is Lakota Pointe - a government housing project right across from the school.
This is one of the places where we are doing the Emmanuel TV Backpack Program.
It is Friday, and we have come out and made sure that all of the youth have gotten a backpack,
with six different meals inside of them.
Many of them are from broken homes or homes where it's only the mother and themselves.
Therefore, it's all because of the generosity of the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV partners.
They have assisted us and provided the resources to be able to support them and to let them know
that they should stay in school.
That's the message from the man of God that they should stay in school.
When their purpose is clear, their life will have meaning. This is the message that we're passing on to them.
That when their purpose, their dreams and goals are clear then their life will have meaning.
And to also let them know to never underestimate the mind. That when you decide what you want to do,
then your mind will help you figure out how to do it.
So this is the message that we have been passing on to them and we will continue.
You've seen many of them get their Emmanuel TV Backpacks,
and every week we will continue to fill it up for them. Especially on the weekends,
we will fill it up for them because many of them only really eat when they go to school.
A lot of them when they come back home it's more of a challenge. Many of them are at home by themselves,
because being in single parent homes means that the parent is often at work.
Therefore, we are providing them with meals that are very easy to make by themselves.
Once again, Emmanuel! Indeed, God is with us.
Emmanuel TV Backpack Program.
Remember, as we said before. We are passing on these encouraging words.
We have seen a lot of things happen from teen suicides to youth committing suicide and it is all because
many of them were affected by peer pressure. They did not measure up to one another's standards.
The message that we pass on is "don't allow yourself to be defined by the opinions of others".
"Love yourself, value yourself." - this is very important. We pass on the message that
the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua says, "Your dream is a photograph of your future".
That's right, your dream is a glimpse into your future. When you're going through hard times, it's that dream,
that will help sustain you through those troubled times.
We also pass on the message that you're born choosers and not losers.
You're born choosers and not losers. The decisions and the choices that they make everyday
will affect their tomorrow. These are the messages that we are passing on to these students
as we refill their backpacks through the Emmanuel TV Backpack Program.
Henry Ford said a hundred years ago that the only thing that matters
is if we made a difference in the life of a child.
And because of the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua, that's what is happening right now.
We're able to make a difference in the lives of these students, in the lives of these children.
Many of them are going home to single parent homes, coming from broken families as well.
We just want them to know and encourage them to stay in school.
We want you to know that, nothing is too big or too small; ever little bit counts.
Emmanuel TV Backpack Program.
Another thing that we want you to know is that in each backpack, every student has a small cash gift on the inside.
This is simply because we want to be a father to the fatherless.
We want to do our part in being a father to the fatherless. The brother to the brotherless.
We can be a sister to the sisterless. It is to show that every little bit counts.
You'll see that a lot of them sometimes look inside, then jump, smile and have a wild look on their face
because on the inside, we have made sure that they have a small cash gift.
These little things mean a lot.
Emmanuel TV Backpack Program.
Emmanuel! Indeed, God is wih us. We are here at Lakota Pointe - a subdivision of the Cincinnati area.
We've got a very special sister here.
Sister, can you tell me how old you are?
I am 15.
15. Wow. Can I get your name?
My name is Zaimir.
I was speaking with her and she let me know that her dreams and her goals are clear.
I want her to tell you what she's going to be.
I want to be an entrepreneur and I want to be the biggest WNBA basketball star.
I am a basketball fan and I believe I can fulfill that dream.
Yes, we believe that as well. We are sponsored and supported by someone that lets us know that,
when you decide what you want to do, then your mind will help you figure out how to do it.
It seems like you have decided on what you want to do so don't let anybody stop you from your dream and goal.
We will continue to come out and support you. Make sure you keep your Emmanuel TV Backpack
so we can keep supporting you every week. Ok.
Thank you.
So look into the camera and say Hello.
Hello!
Thank you.
Bye.
Emmanuel TV Backpack Program.
When we are in the business of giving charitably, I mean sowing into other people's lives,
God who is the dispenser of all good will give us, in His mercy, abundance of good
so that we might enjoy the sufficiency and abound in good works.